Jeffrey Bergier

- **1** +1 (949) 287-1699
- jeffburg (at) jeffburg (dot) com
- www.jeffburg.com
- Higashinakano, Tokyo

TL;DR

iOS and Mac Developer - 4 years

I'm an iOS developer working at Mercari in Tokyo. Mercari is the largest C2C marketplace in Japan. The app is complex and used by millions. I'm a self-taught iOS and Mac developer. Before Mercari, I taught iOS and Mac development at General Assembly and was a full-time iOS developer at Topology Eyewear in San Francisco.

UX Interaction Designer - 4.5 years

I earned my Bachelor of Science in Industrial Design, which focuses on the physical. However, the part of Industrial Design that appeals to me most is problem solving and design thinking. These skills are incredibly beneficial in not just Industrial Design but in all design fields. For 4.5 years I designed complex workflows for enterprise networking products.

Tools

★ Expert

- Sketch
- Adobe InDesign
- Adobe Photoshop
- Balsamiq Mockups

☆ Advanced

- Xcode
- Swift
- Objective-C

O Proficient

- Javascript
- HTML/CSS
- Adobe Illustrator
- Adobe After Effects

Experience

iOS Developer, Mercari Inc., Tokyo

January 2019 - Present

Mercari is the largest C2C marketplace in Japan. The iOS app is used by millions and processes financial transactions, so the tolerance for quality issues is very low. We use technologies such as ReactiveSwift and MicroViewControllers to manage the size and complexity of our views. These tools also make it easier to replace components piece-meal, run quantitative AB tests, and keep our view controllers unit tested.

Engineers at Mercari have diverse skillsets. I am a mentor to Junior iOS developers as well as a a mentee to senior iOS developers. The team is constantly learning, changing, and growing; Its a very exciting environment.

iOS Developer, Topology Eyewear, San Francisco

May 2017 - September 2017, Full Time

September 2017 - December 2018, Part Time Remote Work

Topology Eyewear is an incredible startup in San Francisco. The application performs sophisticated video recording and machine learning to construct an accurate 3D model of the user's face. That 3D model is then used to make glasses that are individually CNC machined to fit. I worked on many of the screens and UI elements for the app. I also worked on integrating the in-app support system that contained full support for deep linking from any part of the app to any other part of the app.

UX Interaction Designer, Riverbed Technology, San Francisco

January 2013 - May 2017

When I started at Riverbed, there was no design team at all. My coworker and I crept our way into every part of the engineering organization and proved the value of UX to the company. Since then, an entire UX team has formed with a Director of UX, a user research, a visual designer, and an interaction designer (me). We all work directly with engineers and product managers, and customers to solve problems.

At Riverbed, our customers have huge networks. Many of our customers have over 1000 Riverbed appliances distributed all over the world. My work involves designing interfaces that make configuring, troubleshooting, and upgrading Riverbed Appliances easy. Because our customers have so many appliances each, the real challenge at Riverbed is making it easy to do all of those operations in bulk.

iOS Dev Teacher, General Assembly, San Francisco

December 2015 - September 2017

I lead a monthly iOS Development 101 workshop at General Assembly. Students range from no programming experience to experienced Java/C#/C++ developers. This can make it hard to keep everyone up to speed without others being bored. I developed the 3 hour curriculum with this in mind. The workshops are an incredible amount of fun and a great lerning experience for all involved.

Volunteer Organizer & iOS Dev Teacher, MobileBridge, San Francisco, 2014 – 2017 User Experience Designer, Woopra, Inc., San Francisco, 2012 – 2013 Organizer / Teacher, Industrial Design Outreach, San Francisco, 2011 – 2012 Genius, Apple Store, Burlingame, California, 2007 – 2009

Education

Bachelor of Science in Industrial Design

San Francisco State University

Industrial Design, San Francisco State University

Fall 2008 - Spring 2011

Product Design, Brunel University, London

Autumn 2009 - Spring 2010